<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE changelog SYSTEM "../dtds/changelog.dtd">

<changelog name="Harmoni ChangeLog">
	<version number="0.0.2" date="2003-09-28">
		<new author='gabe'>ActionHandler::forward($action) can now be called from within an action to continue execution.</new>
		<new author='gabe'>Services::registerObjectAsService() allows you to register an already-instantiated object as a service.</new>
		<change author='gabe'>Services::requireService() now returns the started service.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>LanguageLocalizer files can now have comments (designated by '#') and keys/values are trimmed.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>Harmoni->execute() now returns the result from the action if outputHTML = false.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>DebugHandlers now store an internal output level which is used when none is passed to the Printer.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>LoginState now keeps track of both an Active and Logged-in agent.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>Layouts &amp; other VisualComponents now have setLevel() and getLevel() methods and store the level locally.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>Template->output() now accepts a variable length argument list of FieldSets or hash tables.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>Actions are now passed a reference to the Harmoni object.</change>
		<new author='gabe'>Databases now have a toDBDate() and fromDBDate() function to convert to the necessary Date format.</new>
		<new author='gabe'>Completed ActionHandler, LoginHandler and Harmoni classes and services.</new>
		<change author='dobo'>Deprecated the createDatabase() method in DBHandler. Use addDatabase(), instead. This
		change was provoked by the fact that Oracle requires different arguments to instantiate the DB object.</change>
		<new author='gabe'>Added RGBcolor and HTMLcolor classes.</new>
		<change author='gabe'>Finished Layout, Theme and Template.</change>
		<change>AuthenticationMethod includes changed to avoid random unprintable character output.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>FieldSetValidator and RuleSet now take optional argument on validate()/validateAll() functions specifying if errors should be thrown upon failure or not.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>RuleSet can now accept an ErrorHandler to use via setErrorHandler().</change>
		<new author='dobo'>DBHandler can now use a PostgreSQL server and fetching last insert ID works on all integrated DBs.</new>
		<change author='gabe'>layoutHandler now works. Theme integration is to come.</change>
		<new author='max'>Database file storage method.</new>
		<new author='gabe'>Added interfaces for: VisualComponent, Layout, Menu, Content -- all part of the LayoutHandler.</new>
		<change author='gabe'>AuthenticationResult now holds authenticated agent's system name as well as valid methods.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>AgentInformationHandler now handles compiling of search results and returns the appropriate array format.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>AuthenticationMethod::getAgentInformation now returns an associative array of [username]=>array([key1]=>value1,...),...</change>
		<new author='gabe'>ChangeLog now held in an XML file and translated by XSL!</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.0.1" date="2003-07-10">
		<change author='gabe'>Changed AuthenticationMethod to allow for getAgentInformation(username,searchMode) so that one can search for a username/fullname etc as well as get information for a single entry.</change>
		<new author='max'>Added StatisticsHandler.</new>
		<change author='gabe'>Updated DB and LDAP AuthenticationMethods to allow for user-info searching &amp; tested backwards compatibility.</change>
		<change author='gabe'>Changed naming scheme of packages so that they describe more clearly what they DO as opposed to what they CONTAIN.</change>
	</version>
	
	<authors>
		<name short="gabe">Gabe Schine</name>
		<name short="adam">Adam Franco</name>
		<name short="dobo">Dobo Radichkov</name>
		<name short="max">Max Ovsjanikovs</name>
		<name short="eric">Eric Janssen</name>
		<name short="zach">Zach Toups</name>
		<name short="karlie">Karlie Verkest</name>
	</authors>
	<groupid>82873</groupid>
	<reftypes>
		<reftype name="bug">567473</reftype>
		<reftype name="fr">567476</reftype>
	</reftypes>
</changelog>
