<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- 
 @package harmoni.docs
 @copyright Copyright &copy; 2005, Middlebury College
 @license http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html GNU General Public License (GPL)
 @version $Id: changelog.xml,v 1.287 2008/04/26 01:00:12 adamfranco Exp $
 -->
<!DOCTYPE changelog SYSTEM "../dtds/changelog.dtd">

<changelog name="Harmoni">
	<version number="1.8.5" date="The Future">
		<releaseNotes>
		
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-10-24' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Chronology: TimeStamp->asDateAndTime() now returns a real DateAndTime object.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.8.4" date="2008-10-22">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes an omission in the Authorization cache that was
			preventing HTTP authentication from working without cookies.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-10-22' ref='2187465' reftype='segue_bug'  reporter=''>
			AuthZ2: Now properly clearing user-specific information after authentication.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.8.3" date="2008-10-15">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes an error in the Chronology library in which 
			DateAndTime objects were off by a day when created with a year 
			and no day parameter.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-10-15' ref='2112633' reftype='segue_bug' reporter='bryan_carson'>
			Primitives: Chronology's DateAndTime is now not off by a day when created
			with a year and no day.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.8.2" date="2008-10-13">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few small issues. See the change-log for details.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-10-06'>
			AuthN: Now only logging login success so that usage of multiple authentication
			methods doesn't fill the logs with failures when each method is tried.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-10-06'>
			Errors: IP addresses are now included in error logs for anonymous users
			to aid in tracing anonymous intrusion attempts.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-10-13'>
			Primitives: New string parser to handle multiple date formats with times 
			that include time-zone information.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="1.8.1" date="2008-10-03">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few small issues. See the change-log for details.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-09-30'>
			Fixed typo in classname, 'DuplucateKeyDatabaseException' is now 'DuplicateKeyDatabaseException'.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-09-30' ref='1939677' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Request Context: Added new method for accessing current context data.
			
			This provides access to the parameters currently passed-through so that
			they may be passed on to javascript functions.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="1.8.0" date="2008-09-24">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release adds support for IP-range-based group membership,
			user-preference storage, and caching of group membership information.
			
			New database tables must be installed for user-preferences.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-09-24' ref='2102311' reftype='segue_fr' reporter='bryan_carson'>
			Agent: Now supports IP-range-based group membership.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-09-22' ref='2112775' reftype='segue_fr'>
			UserData: New UserData system for storing persistent and per-session
			user preferences.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-09-24'>
			AuthZ2: IsAuthorizedCache now saves the current user's group ids for the
			session to avoid unneeded groups membership searching. This doesn't 
			change execution time too much, but does cut out between 17 and 18 queries
			or statement executions per execution cycle.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.7.0" date="2008-08-27">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release adds the ability to pass session information in the URLs
			to select actions, enabling access to some actions by Flash and other
			clients that do not reliably support cookies for all access.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-08-26' ref='1820865' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Harmoni now allows configuration of actions that allow the SESSION ID in URLs.
			
			If we are using an SID for an action configured to allow it in the url,
		    the Set-Cookie header is overwritten with a bogus one to prevent session
		    fixation.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="1.6.2" date="2008-08-25">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release makes a few improvements to the Request system. See the
			change log for details.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-22' ref='2068136' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Request: PathInfo URLs now do not include empty values as these will 
			break the order of arguments on the receiver side since PHP converts
			double-slashes (//) to a single slash (/) in the PATH_INFO variable.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-08-22'>
			Request: UrlWriters now support moveValueToBeginning() method to
			re-order how parameters appear in the URLs.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-22'>
			Request: RequestContext->mkURLWithBase() now supports addition of
			request-tokens.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.6.1" date="2008-08-14">
		<releaseNotes>
			Fixed a thumbnail generation bug.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-14' >
			ImageProcessor: Now uses the ImageMagick 'identify' command to determine
			if an image has one or more frames (such as a multi-page PDF). Only
			multi-framed images will have the first-frame identifier '[0]' used
			when generating thumbnails.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.6.0" date="2008-08-14">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a number of security issues.
			
			Security issues fixed: 
						
			* Cross-Site Request Forgeries (CSRF) are now eliminated from data-modification
			actions. Read about CSRF at: http://shiflett.org/articles/cross-site-request-forgeries
			* Harmoni can now be configured to use secure/http-only cookies. 
			* Admin actions are now restricted to prevent listing of users and
			ids in the system.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-08-14' ref='2040513' reftype='segue_security' reporter='josh_abraham'>
			Security/Actions: Actions that involve data modification can now be configured
			to require per-user	tokens in the request to prevent Cross-Site Request 
			Forgeries.
			
			Actions can be added to the list by using 
			$harmoni-&gt;ActionHandler-&gt;addRequestTokenRequiredActions().
			
			Once a module/action pair is added to the list, all URLs written to it
			will include the per-user token and that token will be checked before
			the action is allowed to execute.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-14' ref='2040501' reftype='segue_security' reporter='josh_abraham'>
			Security: Harmoni now supports setting the session.cookie_secure and session.cookie_httponly parameters in the harmoni config.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.5.0" date="2008-08-13">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release makes several improvements to the Authorization, Repository,
			and Request systems to support Segue 2. See the change log for details.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-08-07' ref='1820937' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Request: RequestContext now has a new mkUrlWithBase() method that 
			allows the specification of a base-url to be used instead of the
			MYURL constant.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-08-11'>
			Repository: HarmoniRepository's getAssetsByType() method now first loads
			nodes by type to prevent lookups on all nodes. Cuts Segue 'All Visible'
			portal page loading from 65 seconds to 10 seconds.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-12' ref='2048119' reftype='bug' reporter='gabe'>
			AuthZ2: Session-caching of authorizations now works again.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-08-12'>
			AuthZ2: Authorization cache now expires after 10 minutes to prevent
			users with very old sessions from retaining abilities due to cached 
			authorizations.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.7" date="2008-08-07">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes an authorization issue as well as enhances security
			by preventing Javascript from being written to the logs. See the change
			log for details.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-07' reporter='peter_wilkins'>
			AuthZ2: A typo in the view authorization id was preventing cascading-up
			implicit view authorizations from ever being written.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-05' ref='2040255' reftype='segue_security' reporter='josh_abraham'>
			Logging: Log messages are now filtered to prevent Javascript insertion.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-08-04'>
			ErrorHandler: New NoMoreIteratorElementsException available. 
			
			UnimplementedException now includes class and method name of the unimplemented
			method.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.6" date="2008-08-01">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a number of issues that were affecting Segue 2.
			
			Most important is a fix to the image-processor to correctly support
			generation of thumbnails from multi-page PDF files.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-29' ref='2031483' reftype='segue_bug' reporter='tom_coppeto'>
			ImageProcessor: Thumbnail generation from multi-page PDFs now only extracts
			the first page enabling valid thumbnails to be generated and preventing
			extra processing of other pages that was being overwhelmed by very large
			PDFs.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-08-01' ref='2034986' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Sets: Fixed up SQL keys to allow sets to contain an item several times
			at different positions as is allowed in the interface.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-25'>
			AuthZ2: Fixed up Hierarchy Exceptions to use valid Exception classes.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.5" date="2008-07-24">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few minor issues that were causing problems with
			Segue.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-23' ref='2021574' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Request: PathInfoRequest handler now replaces encoded question marks
			"%3F" with a "_quest_" placeholder to get around an issue with Apache's
			mod_rewrite accidentally decoding encoded question marks in some situations.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-22'>
			GUI2: Now forces the empty namespace for the theme id parameter to 
			prevent the CSS from breaking when namespaces are not closed.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.4" date="2008-07-21">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes an issue with Authorization settings for members of 
			groups the ids of which contain quotes.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-21' ref='2023672' reftype='segue_bug' reporter='hector_vila'>
			AuthZ/PDO: Adding temporary work-around for bug 2023672/ PHP bug 41125
			
			A PHP/PDO bug is resulting in problems when escaped quotes exist in an SQL
			string that is then prepared. This is occurring for users who are members
			of groups that have a quote in their LDAP DN.
			
			This is the second time this bug has bitten us, this time in the AuthZ2
			AuthorizationCache. The first workaround was added to fix Harmoni bug 1970447.
			
			See: https://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=1970447&amp;group_id=82171&amp;atid=565234
			See: http://slug.middlebury.edu/~afranco/PHP_PDO_segfault/
			See: http://bugs.php.net/bug.php?id=41125
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.3" date="2008-07-17">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes several issues with Themes and Logging.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-17' ref='2018232' reftype='segue_bug'>
			GUI2: Output handler now sends theme options in the theme CSS URL.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-17' ref='2009090' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Logging: Now returns an empty string if there is no backtrace.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.2" date="2008-07-11">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release includes a minor improvement to support Segue.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-07-11'>
			AuthZ2: More use of prepared statements in Authorization fetching
			methods to speed up Segue's 'roles' UI.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.1" date="2008-07-10">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release adds some minor improvements to support Segue.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-06-18'>
			GUI2: GUIManager now can be configured to link to theme styles at a URL.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-07-08'>
			DatabaseManager: New NoSuchTableDatabaseException to classify missing
			table errors. Currently only supported by MySQL.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-07-10'>
			Agent: The Users group now includes all groups except itself and Everyone
			and all agents except Anonymous. This enables the Users group to be a
			stand-in for any user who has been authenticated.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.4.0" date="2008-06-16">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release includes two improvements:
			
			* The ActionHandler now supports the specification of default parameters
			  to be used when the default module and action are used.
			  
			* New methods for converting strings to UTF-8 and converting 'smart-quotes'.
			  Usage of this new String->makeUtf8() method requires PHP to be compiled
			  with the --enable-mbstring option.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-06-16' ref='1995141' reftype='segue_fr'>
			ActionHandler/HarmoniConfig: Can now specify default parameters along
			with the default module and action.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-06-16' ref='1993889' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Primitives: String and HtmlString now include a new method for converting
			non-UTF-8 characters to UTF-8: makeUtf8
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="1.3.5" date="2008-06-13">
		<releaseNotes>
			Harmoni versions 1.2.0 through 1.3.4 included a bug in AuthZ2 in 
			which implicit authorizations were not created when new nodes were 
			created with Hierarchy->createNode(). This release fixes that issue.
			
			For other improvements please see the change-log.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-06-12' ref='1991183' reftype='segue_bug'>
			AuthZ2: Fixed AuthZ2 issue where implicit AZs were not being created 
			for new nodes.
			
			This had the effect of causing Admins to not be authorized to view new
			Segue sites. Implicit AZs were created OK in other situations because
			nodes were attached to parents via the addParent() method which triggered
			implicit AZ insertion.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-06-10'>
			Request: Specifying null for a URL value will now remove the key rather
			than setting the value to an empty string.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-06-10'>
			Logging: Can now return a list of existing categories.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-06-10'>
			AuthNMethods: Visitor registration system now logs registration and
			email confirmation steps.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-06-10'>
			AuthNMethods: Visitor registration email now informs the user that 
			their username is their email address.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-06-13'>
			StatusStars: Now keeps the output buffers in the correct order.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.3.4" date="2008-06-09">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release adds support for a visitor registration authentication
			method.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-06-05' ref='1820894' reftype='segue_fr'>
			AuthNMethods: New Visitor Authentication method that allows for
			visitor registration.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="1.3.3" date="2008-06-03">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few issues that were affecting Concerto, most
			notably, several issues with safe-mode restrictions when creating
			or extracting tar archives. 
			
			Harmoni now includes a custom version of the Archive/Tar PEAR library 
			with a fix for bug #14058 that prevents proper extraction of archives
			with Safe Mode on.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-06-02' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			AuthZ: Fix to old authorization implementation that was causing function
			types to get messed up on installation of Concerto.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-06-03' ref='1912944' reftype='concerto_bug'>
			Archiving: Harmoni now includes a custom version of Archive/Tar with a fix for
			bug #14058 that was preventing decompression of tar files that have a
			directory hierarchy when in PHP 5.2+ with Safe Mode on.
			
			http://pear.php.net/bugs/bug.php?id=14058
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-06-03' ref='' reftype='fr'>
			Repository: Repository::getAssetsBySearch() now recognizes a null-type properties object.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.3.2" date="2008-05-23">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few errors affected a few users, notably a work-around
			for a PHP/PDO bug that results in segmentation faults when escaped quotes 
			exist in an SQL	string that is then prepared. This is occurring when
			checking authorization for users who are members of groups that have a 
			quote in their LDAP DN.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-23' ref='1970447' reftype='bug'>
			PDO: Adding temporary work-around for bug 1970447/ PHP bug 41125
			
			A PHP/PDO bug is resulting in problems when escaped quotes exist in an SQL
			string that is then prepared. This is occurring for users who are members
			of groups that have a quote in their LDAP DN.
			
			
			See: https://sourceforge.net/tracker/index.php?func=detail&amp;aid=1970447&amp;group_id=82171&amp;atid=565234
			See: http://slug.middlebury.edu/~afranco/PHP_PDO_segfault/
			See: http://bugs.php.net/bug.php?id=41125
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-22' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Hierarchy: Fix to the older Hierarchy implementation to prevent errors
			when not using Harmoni_Db.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.3.1" date="2008-05-22">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a minor theming issue that was affecting the Polyphony
			log-browsing actions.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-21' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Gui2: Theme URLs now do not get messed up in names-spaced actions like
			log-browsing.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.3.0" date="2008-05-20">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release adds support for a new Theming system, Gui2. Gui2 
			simplifies the expectations of themes to allow a wider range of possible
			implementations and storage techniques.
			
			As well, a number of minor bugs have been fixed.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-05-14' ref='1820834' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Gui2: New Gui2 system re-envisions the way themes are defined and accessed.
			Rather than forcing themes to be concrete classes, a variety of theme
			sources can be defined that can each determine how their themes are
			stored and retrieved. 
			
			Themes may have options for varying their color scheme or other attributes, 
			but this is an optional level of compliance, not forced. Similarly,
			themes may optionally support modification.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-05-20' ref='' reftype='fr'>
			Gui/Gui2: The EMPHASIZED_BLOCK has be deprecated and a SIDEBAR_BLOCK
			added to enable better syntactical alignment between usage and theme
			definition.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-05-20'>
			Utilities/Filing: A simple Filing interface has been added to provide
			an abstraction on 'files'. These are currently used in the new Gui2 system
			to get and set Thumbnails and theme images.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-05-13' ref='' reftype='fr'>
			AuthNMethods: HttpAuth-token collector now can accept a user-function
			array instead of just a string.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-20' ref='1964729' reftype='segue_bug' reporter='jeff_merriman'>
			Request: Multiple calls to startNamespace(null) were not filling the
			name-space stack with null name-spaces, so when endNamespace() was then
			called, extra non-null name-spaces were removed from the stack.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-05-13' ref='' reftype='fr'>
			Request: Replacing slashes in path-info URLs.

			Apache denies requests where the path-info includes %2F, the encoded version
			of the forward slash, /. This is done to aid the security of CGI scripts,
			but means that we can't pass encoded slashes in PATH_INFO parameters.
			
			This fix replaces slashes with the string, '_slash_', when writing the
			path info urls and reverses that replacement on read.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-13' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Primitives: Fixed static/non-static method access in Chronology.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-14' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Primitives: Adding in a pass by reference to fix an Chronology bug.
			
			The _normalize() method needed an array passed by reference to act on.
			In the PHP 5 migration the reference got deleted by accident, so the
			normalization wasn't being done. This had the effect of not rolling over
			days when adding durations that bumped a date and time over the length of
			a day.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.2.0" date="2008-05-05">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release includes a new implementation of the Authorization and Hierarchy
			services along side of the original implementations. This new 'AuthZ2' implementation
			stores hierarchy and authorization data in a set of tables with foreign-key
			constraints/triggers to manage the removal of authorizations when nodes
			in the hierarchy are dropped. As well, AuthZ2 stores implicit authorizations
			as rows in an implicit_azs table to allow simple lookups without the need of
			traversing the hierarchy at read-time. AuthZ2 enables Segue to run approximately
			600% faster, with some operations seeing 2000% decreases in execution time.
			
			Additional improvements in this release include more robust Harmoni_Db support,
			as well as fixes to Tagging, Language, and Database services.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-24' ref='1951075' reftype='fr'>
			AuthZ2: New Authorization/Hierarchy package stores implicit authorizations
			as rows in their own table so that they can be quickly read at the
			expense of a small increase in writing time and storage space.
			
			Either AuthZ2 or the original Authorization and Hierarchy implementations
			can be used by Harmoni applications as these implementations are independent
			of one another. A migration script for moving hierarchy and authorization
			information out of The original tables and into the AuthZ2 tables can be
			found at harmoni/core/oki2/AuthZ2/migration.php
			
			Please note that in AuthZ2 the 'edu.middlebury.authorization.view' function
			has the property of cascading up the hierarchy as well as down. This property
			is needed by our Segue and Concerto applications and the lack of it in 
			the original implementations required the use of the isAuthorizedBelow()
			function. All other authorization functions cascade down only.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-18'>
			AuthorizationManager: Now can be configured to use Harmoni_Db.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-21'>
			Authorization: Cleaned up query syntax to do use addWhereEqual(), addWhereLike(), etc
			methods rather than manually building WHERE strings.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-24'>
			Authorization: Now explicit AZs do not create identical duplicate implicit AZs when
			searching for AZs for any agent.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-21'>
			Authorization: Added AuthorizationManager::getIsAuthorizedCache() method
			to access the IsAuthorizedCache used by the current AuthorizationManager
			for queueing of qualifier-ids. This new method and its usage by the Repository
			and Authentication systems allows swapping of the Authorization-Hierarchy implementation.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-21'>
			Authorization/Hierarchy: Now relying on type-hinting for validation of object
			parameters rather than using the ArgumentValidator.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-21'>
			Hierarchy: Cleaned up query syntax to do use addWhereEqual(), addWhereLike(), etc
			methods rather than manually building WHERE strings.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-18'>
			IdManager: Now can be configured to use Harmoni_Db.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-18'>
			Harmoni_Db: Insert now ensures that at least one row of values exists.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-24'>
			Harmoni_Db: Can now set Auto-Increment table/key for retrieving the
			last insert id from INSERT query executions.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-25' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Harmoni_Db: Backtrace collection now works when preparing queries directly
			as well as from query-building objects.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-29' ref='' reftype='fr'>
			Harmoni_Db: It seems that only the MySQL PDO adapter supports buffered
			queries, so result buffering is now done in PHP in Harmoni_Db rather
			than in the adapter. Hopefully performance won't take too much of a hit
			and portability will be preserved.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-01' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Harmoni_Db: New Harmoni_Db query result class for INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE queries.
			
			Harmoni_Db_SelectResult is now only for SELECT results. Other modes of
			operation for INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE queries have been moved to a new
			class, Harmoni_Db_InUpDeResult.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-18'>
			DatabaseManager: InsertQueries will now convert numeric parameters to
			strings rather than throwing InvalidArgumentExceptions.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-25' ref='' reftype='fr'>
			DatabaseManager: Now sends null instead of NULL for auto-increment columns 
			for better compatibility.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-28' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			DatabaseManager: Fix to transaction exception class name.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-18'>
			ErrorHandler: Exceptions can now define a getHtmlMessage() method and have
			this HTML-formatted message printed without entity conversion.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-18'>
			Harmoni_DOMDocument: Now defines getHtmlMessage() in its ValidationException
			to print more legible messages.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-18' ref='1940489' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Tagging: Can now access information about individual applications of a tag
			via TagManager::getTagInfoForItem().
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-18' ref='1940489' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Tagging: Can now specify a time-stamp when setting a tag for a particular
			agent.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-05-01' ref='' reftype='bug'>
			Language: Since putenv() is restricted in safe-mode, errors are now
			suppressed when calling it with safe-mode on as it is not needed in 
			many systems.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.1.0" date="2008-04-11">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release adds a new database access and SQL query system, Harmoni_Db.
			Harmoni_Db is an extension of Zend_Db and adds Harmoni query-building 
			syntax to the Zend_Db system. Through Harmoni_Db, prepared SQL statements
			are now supported and can be configured for use in the Hierarchy and AgentManagement
			services for increased performance.
			
			See the change log for additional fixes and improvements.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-03' ref='1814119' reftype='fr'>
			Harmoni_Db: New Zend_Db and PDO-based database abstraction and query
			writing system.
			
			See the following page for more information: http://harmoni.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/Harmoni_Db
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-03' ref='1814119' reftype='fr'>
			Harmoni_Db: Required Zend_Db sources are now included with Harmoni. No extra 
			installation is needed.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-04'>
			DatabaseManager: Can now trace query-calling functions.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-08' ref='1814119' reftype='fr'>
			Hierarchy: Can now optionally use Harmoni_Db for some common queries.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-08'>
			Hierarchy: Now only catches UnknownIdExceptions to allow database exceptions
			to bubble up.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-08' ref='1814119' reftype='fr'>
			AgentManagement: Can now optionally use Harmoni_Db for some common queries.
		</new>
		<fix author='alex,adam' date='2008-04-04' ref='1934661' reftype='segue_bug'>
			AgentManagement: LDAP search cache now is per baseDN.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-08'>
			Debug: added var_dump_pre() function for doing a var_dump() with pre-format tags.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-03'>
			ErrorHandler: now prints the full file path in the backtrace file title.
		</fix>		
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-04-09' ref='1938748' reftype='segue_bug'>
			ErrorHandler: Now filters request values whose names contain 'password'
			and other configurable request values out of logs, inserting a placeholder.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-10'>
			Request: Can now set or override a request parameter through a new setRequestParam() method.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.6" date="2008-04-02">
		<releaseNotes>
			In addition to a few bug fixes elsewhere, this release improves the
			LanguageLocalizer to support all ISO 639-3 language codes and adds
			native translation of language names from Wikipedia.org.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-02'>
			Request: Can now pass additional variables to mkURLWithPassthrough().
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-02' ref='1897447' reftype='segue_fr'>
			AgentManagement: LDAP connector now caches returned info in the session 
			to dramatically	improve speed of repeated data access. (about 3x)
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-02' ref='1931215' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Hierarchy: HierarchyCache now throws classed exceptions rather than generic ones.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-02' ref='1930276' reftype='bug' reporter='jose_accino'>
			Language: Now supports three-letter language codes such as 'ave_VE'. 
			Also supports secondary three-letter codes such as 'cym', 'wel', and 'cy' for 'Welsh'.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-02'>
			Language: Country names are now nicely mixed-case rather than all upper.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-02' ref='1930280' reftype='bug' reporter='jose_accino'>
			Language: Now does a 
			
			putenv('LANG='.$this->_lang); 
			
			in addition to 
			
			setlocale(LC_ALL, $this->_lang);
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-04-02' ref='1930291' reftype='fr' reporter='jose_accino'>
			Language: New methods LanguageLocalizer::getCurrentLanguageCode() and
			LanguageLocalizer::getCurrentCountryCode() to provide access to the simple
			versions of the current codes.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-04-02'>
			Language: Added new ISO 639-3 language list. Added language-name translation
			table from Wikipedia.org. Can now return language names in native form or in
			specified translation order.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.5" date="2008-03-25">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release includes some improvements to enable more flexibility in
			the Request system as well as fixes a few minor issues.
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-03-20'>
			Request: Can now override the specified module and action. This is
			useful to allow entry points to force usage of a particular action.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-03-20'>
			Request: Can now retrieve parameters from a url string.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-03-20'>
			Request: Can now retrieve name-spaced parameters from a url string.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-03-20'>
			ErrorHandler: Now escapes entities in back-traces.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-03-20'>
			Architecture: Now throws an UnknownActionException if no module is specified.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-03-17'>
			Agent: AgentManager now throws an UnknownIdException instead of a generic
			one when an agent doesn't exist with the id specified.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.4" date="2008-03-12">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release updates the default case of column names in several minor database tables.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-03-11'>
			GUI: Table columns are now all lowercase.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.3" date="2008-03-10">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few bugs.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-03-06' ref='1908762' reftype='segue_bug' reporter='bryan_carson'>
			Request: PathInfo Request variables are now encoded with rawurlencode()
			instead of urlenced() to encode spaces with '%20' instead of '+'. This
			prevents some decoding issues when values contain spaces.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-03-06' ref='1907111' reftype='fr'>
			ArgumentValidator: Now throws an InvalidArgumentException on validation fail
			to allow for easier catching of this type of error.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-03-06' ref='1907239' reftype='fr'>
			Logging: Logging Items must now implement a new AgentNodeEntryItemInterface.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-03-06'>
			Logging: HarmoniWritableLog now correctly implements the WritableLog interface.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-03-06'>
			SimpleTableRepository: Internal IdManager now implements IdManager.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-03-06' ref='1824819' reftype='bug'>
			SimpleTableRepository: Now converts search criteria to the proper character set.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.2" date="2008-03-03">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few minor bugs.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-02-29'>
			Primitives: Fixed a Date method definition to define it as static.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-02-28'>
			GUI: Fixed error in Blank component constructor.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-02-26' ref='1899163' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Request: Path-info handler now doesn't raise a notice when no action
			is passed.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-02-26' reporter='jose_accino'>
			AuthN: Removed legacy class HarmoniAuthenticationType.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.1" date="2008-02-21">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes an issue in which Cookie values were being appended
			to some URLs. Also fixes a few other typos and bugs.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-02-19' ref='1896959' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Request: Cookie values are now stripped out of URLs made with mkURLWithPassthrough().
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-02-19'>
			AuthZ: Fixed issue in default Type constructors.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-02-21'>
			DatabaseManager: The DuplicateKeyDatabaseException now extends the 
			QueryDatabaseException as it occurs due to problems with a query.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.0" date="2008-02-15">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release includes a newly generated set of the O.K.I. OSIDs as
			PHP5 interfaces instead of concrete classes. As well, a number of bug
			have been fixed and the reliability of PATH_INFO-based urls has been 
			improved.
		</releaseNotes>
		<important author='adam' date='2008-02-06'>
			The O.K.I. OSID interfaces have all been converted from classes
			with die() statements to actual PHP 5 interfaces. 
		</important>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-02-06'>
			OSIDs: The O.K.I. OSID interfaces have all been converted from classes
			with die() statements to actual PHP 5 interfaces. 
			
			Class typing has been added to all OSID method declarations.
			
			Class-constants which were bound as static methods to support
			PHP 4 are now actual class constants.
			
			OsidExceptions now extend the base 'Exception' class.
			
			The DataManager's 'Record' class has been renamed 'DMRecord' so that
			it will not conflict with the OSID 'Record'.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-02-14'>
			Primitives: HtmlString can now take additional protocols to pass unchanged
			through the cleanXSS() method.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-02-07'>
			Moved Type::fromString(Type $type) to HarmoniType class.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-01-31'>
			Agent: New search method for searching based on agent properties.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-01-28'>
			Request: PathInfo and GET url writers now support arrays of parameters
			(such as from a multi-select).
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-01-25'>
			Repository: Assets can now have their Creator and Creation/Modification
			dates force-set, enabling retention of these properties when importing
			from backup.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-01-25'>
			RequestContext: Now provides help methods to interpret URLs written
			by the system.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-01-24' ref='1891413' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Repository: When updating to null values in the FILE record, data rows are 
			now deleted directly rather than updated to null values.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2008-01-23' ref='1815898' reftype='fr'>
			New Harmoni_DOMDocument that adds on a few helper methods and work-arounds
			to the default PHP5 DOM implementation.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-01-23'>
			Agent now requires needed HtmlString class.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-02-15' ref='1854967' reftype='segue_bug'>
			ImageProcessor: Multi-page PDF files seem to not give an exit code when
			thumbnail generation fails. Thumbnail existence is now manually checked
			with file_exists() to prevent errors from coming through.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-02-15' ref='1871570' reftype='segue_bug'>
			RequestContext: Can now get the module and action listed in a url.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.8" date="2008-01-15">
		<releaseNotes>
			A minor fix to Group searching.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2008-01-15' ref='1872249' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Agent: Token search now ensures uniqueness of Ids.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.7" date="2008-01-14">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few minor issues.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-01-04'>
			ErrorHandler: Now prints the error and/or exception code.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2008-01-04'>
			Database: MySQL database now throws a DuplicateKeyException on error code 1062.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.6" date="2007-12-20">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few minor bugs.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-12-20' ref='1854956' reftype='segue_bug'>
			GUI: Can now pass in components to use as non-blank placeholders in case the 
			placeholder never gets replaced.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-12-17'>
			GUI: Moving table-width definitions to style tags to aid validation.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-12-17'>
			GUI: Removing empty width attributes from table data.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-12-17'>
			GUI: Removing 'px' from the values of cellpadding and cellspacing attributes.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-12-14'>
			AuthN: Fixed error in isUserAuthenticatedWithAnyType().
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.5" date="2007-12-12">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release adds a few minor fixes and a few minor cleanup changes. It
			also includes the addition of HTML cleaning support, available through the
			HtmlString 'primitive' class. This support can be used by client applications
			to strip HTML markup of tags and attributes that might result in XSS attacks.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-12-07' ref='1845759' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Agents: Agent display names are now stripped of XSS-vulnerable-markup.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-12-06' ref='1845757' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Primitives: HtmlString now allows cleaning of potential cross-site-scripting
			(XSS) markup from html. 
			
			Cleaning is done using the safehtml library	by Roman Ivanov
			(http://pixel-apes.com/safehtml/?page=safehtml).
			
			Use the HtmlString::getSafeHtml($aString) method to clean HTML strings
			or use the cleanXSS() instance method of HtmlString.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-12-06'>
			Shared: A new interface, Harmoni_Iterator, defines the additional methods
			beyond those in OSID v2 that Harmoni's iterators provide and use.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-12-03'>
			Request: Can now get the module and action from a UrlWriter.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-12-03'>
			Hierarchy: Now more reliably throws an UnknownIdException when no node is found.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-30' ref='1841763' reftype='bug'>
			Agent: Fixed an error in the display name update implementation.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.4" date="2007-11-13">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few minor issues with the Error Handler.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-12' ref='1829095' reftype='bug'>
			ErrorHandler: Categories and priority types are now separate logging fields.
			
			Uncaught Exceptions all have priority 'Uncaught Exception' and a category
			which is their type or class-name as applicable.
			
			Errors use their type as their priority and have no category.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-12' ref='1827143' reftype='bug'>
			ErrorHandler: Backtrace arguments are now escaped to prevent invalid characters from 
			killing log-browsing HTML or causing XSS injections.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.3" date="2007-11-09">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few minor bugs and adds the ability to attach externally-defined
			groups (such as from LDAP) underneath locally defined groups.
			
			Changes to the Agent tables require running a database updater script:
			harmoni/core/DBHandler/db_updater.php
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-05'>
			Authorization: The HarmoniAuthorizationManager now accepts null arguments
			to getExplicitAZs() as per the OSID.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-07' ref='1824880' reftype='segue_fr'>
			Agent: The OSID Agent implementation now supports the addition of externally
			defined groups (such as from LDAP) as subgroups under locally defined groups.
			This allows for locally defined amalgamations of externally defined groups
			into one entity.
			
			This relationship is stored outside of the hierarchy in a new database table
			and requires a database update.
		</fix>
		<important author='adam' date='2007-11-07'>
			Changes to the Agent tables require running a database updater script:
			harmoni/core/DBHandler/db_updater.php
		</important>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-11-07'>
			Shared: The MultiIteratorIterator now throws an exception if arguments
			are inadvertently passed to the constructor.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-07'>
			ErrorHandler: Now checks for trace elements to be set to prevent notices.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-08' ref='1828488' reftype='segue_bug'>
			Repository: Asset create-date now properly set.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.2" date="2007-11-01">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few minor bugs and improves support for using the
			Harmoni Architecture via a command line interface.
		</releaseNotes>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-10-25'>
			ErrorHandler: Now allows specifying of which log to write to.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-25'>
			Logging: Fixed error that occurred when browsing to more than 50 log entries.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-30'>
			Repository: The SimpleTableRepository now will convert character encodings
			to UTF-8 if a non-UTF-8 encoding is specified in the configuration.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-30'>
			Chronology: Fixing E_STRICT-level runtime notices.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-11-01'>
			ErrorHandler: Now checks for the existence of various $_SERVER properties
			as they won't be available when running in CLI.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-11-01'>
			Architecture: Harmoni::execute() can now be called multiple times with
			different actions.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-11-01'>
			Architecture/CLI: New request handling support for command line scripts.
			
			A CommandLineRequestHandler will read parameters of the form --name='value'
			into the RequestContext for usage by Harmoni and actions, allowing the
			action system and RequestContext system to be fully utilized by command-line scripts.
			
			A CommandLineOutputHandler simply passes returned and printed text to
			stdout, ignore the HTTP specific header() calls and HTML formatting.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-11-01'>
			ActionHandler: Now throws an UnknownActionException when the specified
			action is not found, allowing for special-case handling of this common
			Exception.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.1" date="2007-10-22">
		<releaseNotes>
			This release fixes a few issues that were missed in the last point release.
		</releaseNotes>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-22'>
			ErrorHandler: Now doesn't halt if exceptions are thrown during error logging.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-22'>
			GUI: Font validator rules now properly fit the parent classes interface.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.13.0" date="2007-10-22">
		<releaseNotes>
			New in this release include the addition of alternate repository
			implementations for reading from simple database tables and federating
			together several different repository implementations.
			
			Also, Be sure to point the database updater script (harmoni/core/DBHandler/db_updater.php)
			at your harmoni databases to add new columns that changed in harmoni-0.11.0 
			and harmoni-0.12.0.
			
			Changes to the Logging tables require running a database updater script:
			harmoni/core/DBHandler/db_updater.php
		</releaseNotes>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-05'>
			A new repository implementation, SimpleTableRepository, exposes simple database
			table rows as Assets.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-05'>
			A new RepositoryManager implementation, FederationRepositoryManager, 
			allows the usage of multiple Repository implementations.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-10-05'>
			Many implementations are now throwing OsidExceptions such as the 
			UnimplementedException, UnknownIdException, etcetera, to allow these
			to be caught separately from generic errors.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-10-05'>
			AuthZ: The Authorization caching system now searches for and verifies
			the existence of qualifier Ids passed to it. It caches a list of 
			unknown ids and throws an UnknownId Exception when asked about that
			qualifier. This change prevents the AuthorizationCache from continually
			rechecking authorizations for qualifiers it will never match, such as
			those in non-HarmoniRepository Repository implementations.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-05'>
			AuthN/LDAP: Previously, when users where members of objects that were not
			under the baseDN, searching for parent groups fell into an infinite loop.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-08'>
			SQL: Adding a harmoni-0.11.0 database updater that will add the 'creator'
			field to the dr_asset_info table.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-09'>
			Custom error_handling function.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-10-09' ref='1810364' reftype='bug'>
			The HarmoniRepositoryManager object is now passed to the objects it 
			creates rather than being accessed globally from within its implementation
			preventing conflicts when multiple RepositoryManager implementations
			exist.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-10'>
			Fixing a number of E_STRICT notices and improving the class and interface
			hierarchies.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-10'>
			Improved Error and Exception handling class, HarmoniErrorHandler. Adds
			unified Error and Exception printing and logging.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-11'>
			DatabaseManager: Can now add LIKE clauses to query objects.
		</new>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-11'>
			DatabaseManager: Can now add sub-queries to the FROM clause via a new
			addDerivedTable($subQuery, $joinType, $joinCondition, $alias) method.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-11'>
			Logging: Log-browsing has been dramatically speeded up by re-factoring
			its queries and indexes.
		</fix>
		<important author='adam' date='2007-10-11'>
			Changes to the Logging tables require running a database updater script:
			harmoni/core/DBHandler/db_updater.php
		</important>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-11'>
			Repository: fixing delete repository syntax to work with PostgreSQL.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-12'>
			RequestContext: Now can set the null (no namespace) namespace.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-12'>
			Authorization: Fixed invalid static calls to instance methods.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-12'>
			ErrorHander: Exceptions and Errors are now printed in a plain text mode when 
			scripts are called from the command line environment.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-10-17'>
			Removing unneeded $harmoni parameters from Action Source methods.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-10-22'>
			Authorization: Fixed type description searching. Only Domain, Authority, and
			Keyword define the type.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.12.3" date="2007-09-25">
		<change author='adam' date='2007-09-25'>
			ImageProcessor: Now throws exceptions when ImageMagic fails.
		</change>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-09-25'>
			GUI: New 'UnstyledMenuItem' element.
		</new>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-09-21'>
			GUI: MenuLinks with Additional HTML now put that additional HTML in the 
			themed part of the element.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-21'>
			Hierarchy: Catching 'not found' Exceptions added in 0.12.2 in cases where no results
			should exist.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.12.2" date="2007-09-20">
		<change author='adam' date='2007-09-19'>
			Removed the legacy StorageHandler. If this functionality is needed in the future,
			the Filing OSID is more appropriate.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-19'>
			Updated PhpDoc comments to generate properly.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-17'>
			Agent: Fixed column type-mismatch in Agent table definition.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-17' reporter='jose_accino'>
			DBHandler: SQLUtils::runSQLdir() now explicitly sorts SQL files 
			and runs them in alphabetical order.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-14'>
			Repository: Fixing PHP notices.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-09-14'>
			Hierarchy: Adding some error-checking and Exceptions on errors.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.12.1" date="2007-09-14">
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-14'>
			Updating the MySQL Hierarchy and Scheduling table definitions to work with
			fixes in harmoni-0.12.0.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.12.0" date="2007-09-13">
		<important author='adam' date='2007-09-11'>
			In order to support PostgreSQL without re-factoring of the Database Handler,
			column names have been all made lowercase. To update a currently populated
			harmoni database to the new names, run the following updater script:
			harmoni/core/DBHandler/db_updater.php
		</important>
		
		<important author='adam' date='2007-09-13'>
			Hierarchy: The node relation and ancestry tables, j_node_node and node_ancestry
			were both missing a reference to the hierarchy for which the node id was valid.
			This could cause conflicts if node ids are repeated in separate hierarchies.
			Existing Harmoni databases will need to have these columns added and the data
			updated.
		</important>
		
		<important author='adam' date='2007-09-13'>
			Scheduling: Two sc_item columns "start" and "end" conflict with reserved
			words in PostgreSQL. Existing Harmoni databases will need to have these columns added and the data
			updated.
		</important>
		
		<change author='adam' date='2007-09-14'>
			DBHandler: The PostGre classes have all been renamed to PostgreSQL
		</change>
		
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-13'>
			ErrorHandler: Fixed reliance on methods in the HarmoniException class
			when printing.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-13'>
			Fixed numerous MySQL-specific SQL statements that didn't work with PostgreSQL.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-13'>
			Added auto-increment-column designators to appropriate Insert Queries
			so that the sequence-values could be accessed when using PostgreSQL.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-09-11'>
			DBHandler: Can now run an entire directory tree full of SQL files.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-11'>
			DBHandler: Some fixes to the PostgreSQL implementation and tests.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-09-11'>
			DBHandler: New database updater utility. The only function implemented currently
			is to convert column names to lowercase.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-11'>
			ErrorHandler: Fixed HTML syntax error in Exception printing.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-07'>
			Repository: Now properly escapes values in modification date-storing query.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam' date='2007-10-11'>
			Logging: New priority type 'All' allows for browsing of all priority levels at once.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.11.0" date="2007-09-07">
		<important author='adam'>
			As of this version, Harmoni no longer supports PHP4. Please use PHP5 or later.
		</important>
		<change author='adam'>
			GUI: Y-Layout now uses div tags instead of tables to allow the setting
			of child widths.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Removing ampersands for compatibility with other PHP5 code.
			The BBEdit-grep string used for the find and replace was:
			
					(function )&amp;|(=\s?)&amp;([^a-z#])|([^&amp;])&amp;\s?(\$)
			
			replaced with
			
				\1\2\3\4\5
			
			
			
			Special Changes were made to the following files to fix problems introduced 
			in the search and replace for ampersands:
			
					polyphony/main/library/ResultPrinter/ArrayResultPrinter.class.php - getLayout()
					
							- $item = $this->_array[key($this->_array)];
							
							======
							
							+ $item = current($this->_array);
					
					harmoni/core/oki2/repository/HarmoniRecord.class.php - getParts()
							
							* Moved the following line out of the if-statement:
							
							* $activeValue = $allRecordFieldValues[$key]->getActiveVersion();
					
					harmoni/core/oki2/hierarchy/tree/Tree.class.php - _traverse()
							
							* Kept the first parameter being passed by reference. Needed in this case.
		</change>
		
		<fix author='adam' date='2007-09-07'>
			OutputHandler: fixing notices.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-09-05'>
			DBC: Updating the Database Handler to throw from an exception hierarchy
			as well as use PHP5 interfaces.
		</change>
		<change author='adam' date='2007-09-05'>
			Errors: Expunging the old harmoni error handler now that we have exceptions.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Hierarchy: Now properly clones the query object in PHP5.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			GUI: Now can include an xmlns namespace in the &lt;html&gt; tag.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Id: Id can now be transparently cast as a string.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Updating the Agent Package to use PHP5 interfaces to allow for type-checking.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Authentication: Adding methods to access a single current Agent. 
			OSID v3 will specify a single agent authenticated at each time, rather
			than our current multiple case. The methods added are to enable working
			in that sort of paradigm, though they do not map directly to the v3 methods.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>	
			DBHandler: Adding Support for table.column column-syntax.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>	
			Repository: Creation date is now added properly when Assets are created,
			instead of on the first modification.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Repository: Assets can now store and retrieve the id of their creator.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			HarmoniIterator now supports the add($item) method to allow incremental
			addition of items to the iterator.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>	
			Converting all short tags (&lt;?) to the full tags (&lt;?php) for 
			compatibility with more PHP configurations.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>	
			Request: Added methods to ease access to the current module and action.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.10.1" date="2007-04-10">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed a few bugs that prevented Harmoni from running in PHP 5.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.10.0" date="2007-04-05">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Architecture: Improved debug output on Harmoni instantiation errors.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			GUI: Now 'placeholders' can be added to containers to provide support
			for out-of-order addition of components.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Utilities: StatusStars can now be used from a CLI environment.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			DBHandler: Added methods to query objects allow the addition of values
			to queries without requiring the user to add quotes and escaping. Quoting
			and escaping is handled within these methods.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Authorization: Added isAuthorizedBelow() and isUserAuthorizedBelow()
			methods to allow determination as to the availability of the contents
			of a node.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Repository: Added an assetExists() method.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Chronology: Now gets AM/PM correct for 12AM and 12PM
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			RequestContext: Now doesn't add cookie values to the request parameters.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			RequestContext: Now doesn't add the module and action to the list of
			passed parameters.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Agent: Removed debugging lines from Group implementation
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.9.0" date="2006-12-13">
		<new author='adam'>
			AuthN: Added support for administrators to act as another user.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			AuthN: Fixed LDAP dnExists() method to work.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			AuthN: Added support for LDAP Group searching.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Repository: Added support for files stored at remote locations.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			AuthZ: Increased the column length of the authorization agent Id
			to prevent long LDAP DNs from being truncated.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Tagging: Tags could be accidentally added with no value, now cannot.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Tagging: Fixed error to allow Collections with no items to be deleted. 
			Zero numbers of tagged items were causing an error.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Tagging: Now can fetch related tags.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Primitives: ByteSize::fromString() now supports integers.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.8.0" date="2006-12-01">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Chronology: Now handles parsing and display of am/pm-formated times
			between 12:00am and 1:00am properly.
		</fix>
		<important author='adam'>
			Harmoni 0.8.0 is a merging of Harmoni 0.7.10 with work done on the
			harmoni trunk by Tim and John over the summer. The additions on the
			trunk include implementations of the CourseManagement and Scheduling
			OSIDs as well as some GUI-theme-management work.
		</important>
		<new author='tim'>
			Implementation of the CourseManagement OSID.
		</new>
		<new author='tim'>
			Implementation of the Scheduling OSID.
		</new>
		<new author='tim'>
			Implementation of the Grading OSID.
		</new>
		<change author='tim'>
			Changes to GUI system to support theme management.
		</change>
		<change author='tim'>
			AuthN: Additions to the authentication methods to support class
			searching.
		</change>
		<change author='tim'>
			ValidatorRules: Additions to support GUI theme management needs.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.10" date="2006-11-30">
		<fix author='adam'>
			AuthZ: getWhoCanDo() was only returning explicit AZs, in error.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			AuthZ: AuthZ cache was not properly checking newly requested agentIds
			if they didn't correspond to the authenticated agents.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.9" date="2006-11-28">
		<new author='adam'>
			Database: Can now generate the appropriate query string for use in 
			building complex sub-queries.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Actions: Removing need to pass the harmoni object from all actions.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Chronology: Allowing colon date delimiters to support dates from EXIF.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: Generating thumbnails now doesn't update the Asset 
			modification date.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Tagging back-end added.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.8" date="2006-10-25">
		<new author='adam'>
			GUI: New GUI component, SubMenu.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Errors: Now includes User-Agent, Referer, Request URI, GET, and POST
			with the logged backtrace.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Chronology: Fixed a number of PHP notices that were occurring in PHP 4.4.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			ActionHandler: Now strips any non-word characters from the action and
			module strings to prevent dynamic including of files outside of the
			modules directory.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.7" date="2006-08-28">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Chronology: Now parses dates of the form 'August 10th, 2006' and 
			doesn't choke on the 'th'.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			UnitTests: Removed deprecated pass-by-reference call.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Chronology: Fixed error, ClockPrecision must be non-zero as otherwise 
			dates span two days rather than a clock-tick less than 24 hours.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			GUI: The table layout can now handle rendering direction of elements 
			other than Left-Right/Top-Bottom.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			GUI: The XLayout and YLayout can now handle rendering direction of 
			elements other than Left-Right and Top-Bottom.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			ImageProcessor: Now if Image Magick barfs on some multi-page PDFs and 
			generates a single black pixel as a thumbnail, it won't be saved and 
			the nice default icon will be used instead.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.6" date="2006-08-15">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: RepositoryManager now returns false instead of an error 
			if the asset with the specified Id does not exist.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.5" date="2006-08-11">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed incomplete method in RegexValidator rule.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Now can force cookie usage to prevent accidental or intentional 
			session hijacking by the passing of session ids in the url.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Authentication/Authorization: Now can dirty the authentication cache 
			to allow HTTP authentication (interrupting the execution cycle) to 
			update the currently authenticated agent.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Authentication: Now passes an auth type key to the token collectors
			to allow them to differentiate between prompting again for an auth type
			and just trying to get the tokens for another auth type.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			Authentication: Now can pass custom realm and callback function to 
			execute on cancel for the HTTP authentication.
		</change>
		<fix author="adam">
			ErrorHandler: Removed debugging line.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.4" date="2006-08-04">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Chronology: fromString() methods now return null for invalid strings
			rather than doing a die(). 
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: Authoritative values are now only added if a valid
			data object is passed.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.3" date="2006-08-02">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Chronology: Now does not die when fromString is called on an invalid date.
			Returns false instead.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: Now enforces deleting of file/thumbnail data properly. 
			Previously, file records were being orphaned when assets were deleted.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Authorization: Now calls addslashes() on agent and group ids to prevent
			errors when those ids contain apostrophes.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Logging: Improved performance of the LogEntryIterator to
			make a more responsive interface.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			Logging: Errors now log the query string as well as the referrer to
			better trace errors.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.2" date="2006-07-21">
		<fix author='adam'>
			ImageProcessor: Now doesn't try to convert text files as images.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.1" date="2006-06-20">
		<fix author='adam'>
			AuthZ: Quotes in Group Ids were breaking queries.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.7.0" date="2006-06-16">
		<important author='adam'>
			The following 9 queries need to be run on a Harmoni 0.6.x database
			to upgrade it to support the needs of Harmoni 0.7.0:
			
			ALTER TABLE `dm_schema` 
			ADD `active` TINYINT( 1 ) UNSIGNED DEFAULT '1' NOT NULL AFTER `revision` ;
			
			ALTER TABLE `dr_authoritative_values` 
			ADD `fk_repository` VARCHAR( 100 ) NOT NULL AFTER `fk_partstructure` ;
			
			ALTER TABLE `dr_authoritative_values` DROP PRIMARY KEY;
			
			ALTER TABLE `dr_authoritative_values` DROP INDEX `fk_partstructure` , 
			ADD INDEX `fk_partstructure` ( `fk_partstructure` , `fk_repository` ) ;
			
			ALTER TABLE `dr_authoritative_values` 
			CHANGE `value` `value` VARCHAR( 240 ) CHARACTER SET utf8 COLLATE utf8_general_ci NOT NULL ;
			
			DROP TABLE `dr_authority_options` ;
			
			ALTER TABLE `log_agent` ADD PRIMARY KEY ( `fk_entry` , `fk_agent` ) ;
			
			ALTER TABLE `log_entry` ADD INDEX ( `log_name` );
			
			ALTER TABLE `log_node` ADD PRIMARY KEY ( `fk_entry` , `fk_node` ) ;
		</important>
		<new author='adam'>
			RequestContext: Moved output buffer jumping methods to the RequestContext
			as ob_jump() and ob_land() from Chris's StatusStars. StatusStars is now in
			harmoni/core/utilities.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Logging: Reworked db indexes to speed queries.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: Some Repository methods now allow the optional passing in of a
			status indicator which can allow the printing of update status.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			DataManager/Repository: DataManager Records now dynamically add fields
			if SchemaFields have been added to their Schema.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			DataManager/Repository: Adding support for PartStructure/Part data-type
			conversion.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			DataManager/Repository: Adding support for schema/RecordStructure deleting.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Repository: Added support for Record/RecordStructure duplication.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Repository: AuthoritativeValues addition is now an AuthorizationFunction.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Authoritative Values are now per Repository.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			BrowserHistoryManager: Now records full url with all parameters 
			automatically.
		</fix>
		<change author='chris'>
			GUIManager has been updated to reflect the original design in its 
			back-end.  All Style objects are streamlined for programatic interfacing.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: File PartStructures now implement skeletons of Authoritative
			Values methods.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Logging: Ensured that logging is now ready for use before attempting
			to log errors.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			DatabaseManager: Allowing the addition of custom messages for database 
			connection errors.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			ErrorManager: Making Errors more legible..
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.6.1" date="2006-05-19">
		<new author='adam'>
			Shared: New Multi-Iterator Iterator to ease the combining of results
			received as several iterators.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Repository: now caches AssetTypes loaded by getAssetTypes().
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Repository: SQL definition now includes MAX_ROWS and AVG_ROW_LENGTH
			parameters to get over issues with the large table size in the
			dr_file_data table.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			RequestContext: In the request, periods and spaces will get 
			converted to '_'s, so it is now done preemptively
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.6.0" date="2006-05-05">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Now deletes the dr_asset_info record when deleting assets.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Assets and Asset-search-order now support modification and creation times.
		</new>
		<change author="adam">
			Asset::getAssets() now loads assets only on calls to next() rather 
			than right away, saving time and queries when just checking for the 
			existence of children.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Implemented Authority-Lists for Record Parts. These lists are accessed
			through the PartStructure. These lists are intended to be used to 
			provide choices in Asset-editing interfaces. There is no restriction
			that Parts must have values not from the list.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Added added support for getting group information from LDAP.
		</new>
		<fix author='chris'>
			Argument validation for id-strings must allow integers as well, fixed
			in HarmoniId, HierarchyCache, Tree.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Now actually gets the qualifier Id when deleting an authorization.
		</fix>
		<change author="adam">
			Added access to the 'Authenticatable Users' group.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Now caches resized versions of images.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed authorization cache errors that occurred when explicit AZs
			triggered cache hits before implicit AZs were loaded.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed keyword searching to cut search time by 10x. 
			Also fixed several reference errors in the DataManager.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Implemented an OSID Logging.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.5.1" date="2005-02-09">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed table structure to support longer Id lengths.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed return by reference errors that throw notices in PHP 4.4.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Now can add HTML ids to GUI components.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed output HTML tabbing.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			HtmlString now handles CDATA sections and HTML comments.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Comparing Ids via object methods rather than string-values
		</fix>
		<new author='chris'>
			Parts can now automatically convert from a string value into the 
			appropriate data object.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			New methods for manipulating OrderedSets.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.5.0" date="2005-01-10">
		<new author='adam'>
			AuthZ: IsUserAuthorized caching system to dramatically speed authorization
			checking. Look-ahead is currently implemented in the AssetIterator: if
			any assets are returned from the iterator, all elements of the iterator
			are queued for AuthZ caching.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Hierarchy: Fix to Node->isLeaf() allows for faster population of 
			browsing interfaces.
		</fix>
		<change author='chris'>
			Repository: Cleaned up the caching that was taking place with
			file data.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Hierarchy: Improved hierarchy caching algorithm dramatically speeds
			hierarchy loading while retaining unchanged portions of the cache
			during hierarchy modification.
		</change>
		<change author='chris'>
			DataManager: Updated id columns in SQL to support longer keys need 
			in Schemas/fields.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			GUI: New constants defined for GUI Block indexes to allow for more semantic
			definition and standardization of the levels used to aid Theming. 
			Examples include BACKGROUND_BLOCK, STANDARD_BLOCK, WIZARD_BLOCK, 
			EMPHASIZED_BLOCK.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			GUI: StyleProperties can now include arbitrary pre and post HTML to be
			wrapped around the content that they are styling. This allows for
			complex layout of corner and border images around content for instance.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			GUI: New basic theme.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Id: Id table now only retains the most recent value instead of all
			used values, saving on wasted table space.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Removed error suppression from the ActionHandler to allow errors to
			be shown during action-class instantiation.
		</change>
		<change author='chris'>
			AuthN: Improved error handling of LDAP connection errors.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Repository: Keyword searching module in Repository.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Repository: Now supports Repository-specific RecordStructures.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Repository: FileRecords now only have their data fetched on access,
			while their metadata (filename, size, mime-type) are fetched together.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repository: Repository->getAsset() was doing extra work verifying
			the existence of Assets it had just found in its search results.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			Argument validation can now be turned off for production.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Many speed optimizations in Repository, Authorization, and Hierarchy.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Primitives: HtmlString primitive which provides cleaning of HTML text as well
			as trimming of an HTML string to a given number of words while 
			preserving proper tag nesting and closure.
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.4.0" date="2005-10-12">
		<change author='adam'>
			Groups and Agents are now stored in the hierarchy, allowing authorizations
			to be placed on them as qualifiers. This allows for specific authorizations 
			as to who can modify which groups or users.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Added a check for magic_quotes_gpc being Off in harmoni.inc.php.
		</change>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			Fixed all functions returning references to newly created objects in HarmoniAuthorizationManager.
		</fix>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added new method getAllExplicitAZsForAgent() to HarmoniAuthorizationManager.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			The Repository FileRecord now provides access to height and width
			information for images and thumbnails.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Changed OKI agent management to use new Everyone/Anonymous/Users IDs.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added EventListener and EventTrigger to allow easy extensions of our code later.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: can now store with a Schema definition an arbitrary set of parameters
			for whatever is useful. Updated the Repository to use this method of storing extra
			data.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe' ref='102459' reftype='task'>
			Added task-manager link-ability to the change-log.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Added retrieval of $_FILES-type data to the RequestContext and RequestHandler classes.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Updated DR module to use new DataManager.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe' ref='890779' reftype='bug'>
			DataManager now uses unique ids to reference fields instead of purely by label. 
		</change>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			Fixed a number of bugs in the Primitive and StorablePrimitive classes.
		</fix>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			Fixed ISO date and time string parsers.
		</fix>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DBHandler and Databases now implement a getTableList() function.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe' ref='102448' reftype='task'>
			Implemented (but did not yet test) Oracle database connectivity.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Changed DBHandler's toDBDate functionality to automatically format and include
			quotations if necessary for the specific DB type. This became a problem
			for Oracle databases where a function call is necessary for date storage.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added getStringName() to the Database interface and added a method in the DBHandler to allows access
			to the string name based on the database index.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe' ref='116890' reftype='task'>
			All DataManager database queries now free() their results after processing.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			GUIManager now allows for the setting of pre and post HTML. These are 
			HTML tags that need to surround a component. This is primarily used to 
			properly nest form-tags around tables/divs to generate valid XHTML.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Repaired many PHP notices.
		</fix>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			Repaired many PHP notices.
		</fix>
		<fix author='niraj'>
			Repaired many PHP notices.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			The hierarchy cache had a problem where _isCached() was called as a property
			instead of a method, square brackets [] versus parenthesis (), and was breaking
			the cache by creating nodes that were listed as children of other nodes, but did
			not have their parents listed.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			The Chronology Library as well as the dataManager primitives have now
			been moved to core/Primitives and generalized.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			The Time and DateTime classes have been removed and their functionality
			replaced by the new Chronology DateAndTime class.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager:
			
			Records no longer have an active state. They either exist or they don't.
			
			Fields that are deleted now are actually removed from the DB if the Record is
			not version controlled.
			
			getIndices() now returns only the active indices per default, including inactive
			ones only if requested.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added a free() call to the SelectQueryResult classes to free
			memory used by the select query.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Added the chronology library, a PHP implementation of the Squeak (Smalltalk) 
			Kernel-Chronology package and aims to serve as a general PHP 
			class-library for handling, comparing, and operating on chronological 
			objects. The original Smalltalk implementation is licensed under the 
			Squeak License http://squeak.org/download/license.html.
			
			This library includes classes that represent instants in time 
			(DateAndTime, TimeStamp), lengths of time (Duration), spans of time 
			anchored at certain instants (Timespan, Year, Month, Week, Date), as 
			well as recurring instants across a span of time (Schedule).
			
			This library has been designed to support all possible dates, times, and 
			durations, not just those since the UNIX epoch (1970). dates can have 
			positive years (C.E./A.D.) or negative years (B.C.E./B.C.) and Durations 
			have been tested to support lengths of time up to +/- 4 billion years with 
			second-precision. Beyond 4 billion years to the limit of testing (50 billion 
			years) Durations have hour-precision.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added URL-writing functionality as well as centralized processing
			of request-related variables from/to the browser into a family
			of classes related to the RequestHandler. 

			All 'communication' between the browser and the program is now
			abstracted and can be subsequently changed transparently.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			In order to allow for globally unique ids from the IdManager, the
			IdManager now allows for an Id prefix to place on ids. The prefix 
			'id.middlebury.edu-' would lead to ids similar to 
			'id.middlebury.edu-1234567890'. This will allow for multiple IdManagers
			to be used together without each giving out the same Id strings.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			In conjunction with the IdManager's added 'prefix' capabilities,
			the Harmoni SQL table definitions have been updated to support the
			storing of string Ids (currently up to 75 characters) that may have
			originated from the IdManager. Ids generated internally by the database
			remain as integers.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			In conjunction with the IdManager's added 'prefix' capabilities,
			the Harmoni services that store Ids have been upgraded to allow 
			string ids as well as integer ids.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.3.3" date="Never Released">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed some more PHP warnings.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="0.3.2" date="2005-04-14">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Existence of a try() function in the ErrorHandler was throwing parse
			errors PHP5.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Services weren't starting because of case problems with the get_class()
			functions in PHP5.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			clone() is a reserved word in PHP5. All clone methods have been renamed 
			replicate().
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			clone() is a reserved word in PHP5. All clone methods have been renamed 
			replicate().
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Type now validates arguments. ConfigurationPropertiesType now instantiates 
			properly.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Removed unused parameters from several methods that were throwing warnings.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			LanguageLocalizer now uses non-deprecated categories.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			If magic_quotes_gpc is on Harmoni now just strips slashes on the G/P/C
			arrays instead of dying with errors.
		</fix>
		<important author='adam'>
			Harmoni now runs on PHP5 and on Win32 systems in addition to PHP4.3 and
			POSIX systems.
		</important>
	</version>
	<version number="0.3.1" date="2005-04-11">
		<change author='adam'>
			Authentication now plays nicely with GET parameters and maintains them
			around during the authentication sequence.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Agent searching works with new mapping system.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.3.0" date="2005-04-07">
		<change author='adam'>
			New Framework/Architecture-GUI/Theme interaction decouples the Harmoni
			object from the output system. The GUIManager and other OutputHandlers
			extend the OutputHandler abstract class and can be attached to Harmoni.
			A default 'BasicOutputHandler' is used when no other OutputHandler is
			specified.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Services::startService(), Services::stopService(), Services::restartService(), 
			and Services::startAll() are now deprecated and print warnings if used.
			Please use Services::startManagerAsService() and/or Services::getService() 
			instead.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			'Service' classes no longer extend the services interface or use
			start()/stop() methods. These had been designed into Harmoni, but were
			never used and are now removed. start()/stop() methods will NOT be
			called during service starting/stopping.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			OKI version 1 interfaces and implementations have been removed, saving
			2MB of files and cleaning up the source tree.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			The hierarchy's Tree class, HierarchyManager/tree/Tree.class.php, now 
			caches its traversal results. (Savings: 93,529 calls to tree->_traverse(), 
			43 seconds execution time on a 500MHz PC in a 5000-node hierarchy)
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			ValidatorRule objects can now be accessed via static
			XxxxxValidatorRule::getRule() methods, allowing the ValidatorRule classes
			to behave as Singletons and avoid the instantiation of tens of thousands
			of ValidatorRule objects.
		</new>
		<new author='dobo'>
			GUI Manager now complete. ThemeHandler and LayoutHandler have been
			removed.
		</new>
		<new author='nik'>
			GUI Manager saving functionality.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			OsidManagers can now be started and configured by 
			Services::startManagerAsService("name", $context, $configuration);
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Service names can now have aliases.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Authentication is completely handled by the AuthenticationManager
			OSID implementation instead of the LoginHandler/AuthenticationHandler.
			The LoginHandler and AuthenticationHandler have been removed.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			New back-end for managing authentication tokens, agents, and the mappings
			between agents and authentication tokens. This is all contained within
			the core/oki2/agentmanagement/ directory.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			DBHandler now provides methods for transaction handling. Applications
			can be coded to use transactions to ensure atomic writes. Databases
			that do not support transactions will simply ignore the calls. Nested
			transaction calls in MySQL are interpreted so that only the outer 
			transaction is run allowing applications coded to use nested transactions
			to often operate on MySQL 4.0.11+.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Now includes implementations of v2.0 of the O.K.I OSIDs.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Now includes v2.0 of the O.K.I OSIDs.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			AuthorizationManager now handles group membership.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			AuthorizationManager now properly returns implicit AZ corresponding to
			explicit AZs at a parent instead of returning the explicit AZs themselves.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: added function to SchemaManager to generate valid PHP code 
			for a given Schema.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: deleting a value from a Record without version control now 
			actually deletes the value instead of flagging it as inactive.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			The LanguageLocalizer now defines functions for _() and gettext() that
			simply return the passed string, so that localized apps can fail
			gracefully to their native language if gettext is not installed.
		</change>
		<change author='dobo'>
			DBHandler improvements: SQL strings are prettier now. Also added variable
			binding functionality.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.2.0" date="2004-10-26">
		<new author='adam'>
			Added a "MIME" service for sniffing mime types from file extensions.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Added an ImageProcessor service for the resizing of images, generation
			of thumbnails, and other common image processing functions. This service
			can be configured to use multiple modules to handle different file types,
			as available. An example would be using PHP's GD libraries for handling
			jpegs and pngs, while using ImageMagick (via shell_exec()) for tiff,
			psd, pdf, etc. files.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam'>
			DBHandler: PostgreSQL now functions without throwing invalid errors.
		</fix>
		<new author='adam'>
			Digital Repository: Now has a "File" Info structure system for storing
			binary files.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Digital Repository: Now stores Asset dates outside of the
			the data manager.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Harmoni::addPreExecActions($action,...) adds a number of actions to execute before executing the action requested by the end user.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Harmoni::addPostExecActions($action,...) adds a number of actions to execute after executing the action requested by the end user.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Harmoni::executeLogin() executes the LoginHandler and stores the result to avoid discrepancies.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Migrated OKI DR implementation to use new DataManager.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: Records now dynamically update their fetch-mode (how much &amp; what data has been fetched) depending on the operation to be performed. Previous version required one to manually re-fetch records (annoying).
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Function printDebugBacktrace([$traceArray]) will print out a debug_backtrace() in a pretty way.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DataManager: Record::getValuesArray() returns an associative array of all active values in a Record.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DateTime::toString() now has optional parameter to return a shorter M/D/Y for the date instead of Month DD, YYYY.
		</new>
		<fix author='adam' ref='102455' reftype='task'>
			AuthN queries now have slashes added to dbc query values.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' ref='102455' reftype='task'>
			Shared queries now have slashes added to query values.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' ref='102455' reftype='task'>
			Globally added addslashes() calls to quoted values in query strings.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			Fixed LoginHandler problem which was preventing the use of custom
			callback functions.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			A new "Sets" service provides an easy system for the creation, ordering,
			and maintaining of persistent collections of Ids.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added new system for storing primitive data values in objects (all classes implementing the Primitive interface - see harmoni/core/dataManager/primitives)
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Re-worked the DataManager with simpler class names and more flexibility. (see harmoni/core/dataManager)
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added a "revision" to all DataSetTypeDefinitions for later program upgrades (can check revision number to see if the structure is up-to-date instead of comparing every field).
		</new>
		<new author='dobo'>
			GUIManager service, based around CSS, will eventually replace the 
			theme/layout handlers.
		</new>
		<new author='dobo'>
			Implemented the Authorization OSID.
		</new>
		<change author='dobo'>
			Reworked the Hierarchy implementation to use a better data-fetching/caching
			model.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.1.0" date="2004-06-11">
		<new author='dobo'>
			Added a new OKI-Hierarchy implementation (hierarchy2).
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DataManager: added a data type to store OKI-style types.
		</new>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			Bugs in LoginHandler.
		</fix>
		<change author='adam'>
			LanguageLocalizer reworked for easier usage and caching of language
			preferences.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			The DataManager/metaData now uses the OKI Shared Ids instead of its own internal
			id system. This keeps all access to unique ids safely behind the Shared interface.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Themes and layouts have been completely re-worked to support easier use and
			more user control of the themes.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Argument Validator now doesn't fail on string representations of integers;
			i.e. "100" as well as 100 will validate.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Implemented the Digital Repository OSID in Harmoni. The DR uses the Hierarchy OSID,
			the DataManager, and the Shared OSID to provide for high-level access and browsing
			of Assets and their associated data/metadata.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'>
			Services: The Harmoni Services now check for the Error Handler and use that
			to print out errors if it is available. This makes for easier to read backtraces.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			DBHandler: DBHandler now throws fatal errors with an explanation when a query
			fails.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Hierarchy: Implemented the Hierarchy OSID. The Hierarchy supports the storing
			of multiple hierarchies and their nodes in one database. In the current 
			implementation, the entire hierarchy is pulled from the database each load. This
			needs to be re-written to optimize it for fast reads from 100,000+ node
			hierarchy (current Segue at Middlebury has ~50,000 nodes).
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DataManager: added DataSet caching to the DataSetManager. Added support for required fields
			in DataSetTypeDefinitions.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Removed argument validation from DateTime constructor to speed up code by 33%.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: sped up fetching large numbers of DataSets at once (by a factor of two).
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: DataSet::prune() now takes a required VersionConstraint object on which to base the
			pruning process. Handling of pruning Tags is very very messy, but it works.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DataManager: can use DataSetManager::selectIDsBySearch() to search all/some DataSets and return
			a list of DataSets that match the criteria.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: ValueVersion::prune() now deletes itself if the DataSet it is part of is inactive.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DataManager: DataSet::prune() now removes all Tags associated with itself.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.0.5" date="2004-01-09">
		<change>
			Implementation of the OKI SharedManager (HarmoniSharedManager) now uses the HarmoniDataManager's IDManager
			for ID creation.
		</change>
		<fix>
			DateTime::toString() now correctly displays minutes.
		</fix>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Optional third argument to DataSetManager::fetchArrayOfIDs() specifies an array of DataSetTypes to limit the
			query.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Completed the HarmoniDataManager!
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			HarmoniDataManager::setup($dbID) now takes optional second argument including a list of DataSetTypes to
			preload in a single query to save time and Database overhead.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			added FloatDataType, ShortStringDataType. finished up DataManager tagging, cloning, pruning functionality.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			added BooleanDataType to DataManager.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DataSetManager::fetchArrayOfIDs() fetches an array of DataSet ids in one SQL query. 
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			DateTime::compare(date1, date2) returns difference in seconds between two dates.
		</new>
		<fix>
			Typo in constructor for UnknownDBError class.
		</fix>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Harmoni::forward(module,action) is now a synonym for Harmoni::ActionHandler::forward() for convenience.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Classes: Timer and QueryCounter for easy micro-second timing or DB query counting, respectively.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Harmoni::getData has been deprecated and replaced by Harmoni::getAttachedData to avoid ambiguity.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			IDManager::newID() now uses auto_increment DB functionality to reduce query count on compatible
			servers.
		</change>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			DataSet::populate() now sets its own ID to avoid super re-duplication of DataSets in database.
		</fix>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			DateTime::now() now gives correct Hour value. Likewise MySQLDatabase::toDBDate() now adds 1 to hour value
			to give correct 1-24 value. Other DB Types haven't yet been checked.
		</fix>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Modified field in HarmoniDataManager table "datasetfield" from "datasetfield_created" to "datasetfield_modified"
			since it is updated on every commit().
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Extensive work on DataManager. Now works for creating/retrieving datasets with version controls.
		</new>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			Corrected ArgumentValidator call in DBHandler checking for DateTimeInterface instead of DateTime.
		</fix>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added AgentInformationHandler::agentExists($name, [$method]) which steps through each AuthenticationMethod
			and checks for an existing agent.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			LoginState now has better support for Active/Authenticated agents. It should allow one to change
			the active agent without disturbing the actual authentication process.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.0.4" date="2003-12-06">
		<new author='gabe'>
			DateTime class has two new functions: toString() and toMDY() which display
			a full date/time and a MM/DD/YY string, respectfully.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Harmoni::pathInfoParts now contains an array of PATH_INFO elements.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			ErrorHandler has new method getErrorQueue() which returns the error queue in a Queue object.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Harmoni::attachContextData() has been renamed (again) to Harmoni::attachData().
			Context::getData() has been moved to Harmoni::getData().
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Context object now carries an array holding the executed actions path, available
			by referencing Context::actionPath.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			ActionHander and Harmoni: ActionHandler now only passes a reference to the Harmoni
			object to action functions and scripts. Other variables are available here:
			Harmoni::HTTPVars, Harmoni::Context, Harmoni::LoginState.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Removed many .interface.php files to save on load times and unnecessary flexibility.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			LoginHandler no longer throws a default error on login failure. LoginHandler::setFailedLoginError()
			can be used to specify an error to be thrown to the UserError service.
			This change is primarily so that people using different languages won't be locked
			into using English for this error message (a pretty important one).
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			LoginState::attachData() has been moved to Harmoni::attachContextData() and
			LoginState::getData() has been moved to Context::getData() for logical and
			organizational reasons.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>LoginHandler and Harmoni: when LoginHandler is used, 
		the action that is checked for required authentication is now the LAST action
		executed instead of the first. This way, the action that finally ends up being
		executed is the "authoritative" action.</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.0.3" date="2003-11-26">
		<change author='gabe'>Made ActionHandler check for class and method definitions before trying to execute them.</change>
		<new author='gabe'>Added defines in config/services.cfg.php to allow a choice of which major "modules" of Harmoni to load, in order to save on startup time.</new>
		<fix author='gabe'>Numerous bug fixes in Harmoni, ActionHandler, LoginHandler</fix>
		<new author='gabe'>Added a file under core/version.inc.php which holds the current harmoni versions.</new>
		<new author='gabe'>Implemented IDManager class under metaData/ to handle ID generation for the MetaData handler classes.</new>
		<change author='gabe'>Updated HarmoniType OSID implementation to have a constructor that follows OKI's specifications.</change>
		<new>Services class now outputs a debug backtrace upon error.</new>
		<fix author='gabe'>
			Fixed bug in optional arg-list for Services::startService that caused a syntax error
			in eval().
		</fix>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Services class method startService($name) now takes optional
			additional arguments which are passed to the service class
			constructor.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			FormFieldSet class under 'utilities' combines FieldSet functionality
			with keeping track of changed values and easy validation. Intended 
			for HTML Form use.
		</new>
		<change author='adam'> 
			Various fixes to the OSIDs. Added 'requires' for classes being
			extended. Fixed	syntax errors.
		</change>
		<new author='adam'>
			Laid out a skeleton Shared Service implementation. Currently the
			shared manager only provides for the generation of unique IDs using 
			a database.
		</new>
		<new author='adam'>
			Fully implemented the Hierarchy Service, the first of the OKI OSIDs
			to be implemented. The Hierarchy Service supports saving to a
			database as well as memory-only usage.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Harmoni Users's Guide stored locally in XML format. Wrote a
			gen-script in PHP using domxml to make pretty HTML interface.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			LanguageLocalizer now uses gettext() functions instead of
			home-brewed. Included PO generators, "borrowed" from the Horde
			project (www.horde.org).
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>New OKI interfaces, OKI gen-scripts and token
			files added (under harmoni/oki and harmoni/core/tools/oki
			respectively)
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="0.0.2" date="2003-09-28">
		<new author='gabe'>
			ActionHandler::forward($action) can now be called from within an
			action to continue execution.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Services::registerObjectAsService() allows you to register an
			already-instantiated object as a service.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Services::requireService() now returns the started service.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			LanguageLocalizer files can now have comments (designated by '#')
			and keys/values	are trimmed.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Harmoni->execute() now returns the result from the action if
			outputHTML = false.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			DebugHandlers now store an internal output level which is used when
			none is passed to the Printer.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			LoginState now keeps track of both an Active and Logged-in agent.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Layouts &amp; other VisualComponents now have setLevel() and
			getLevel() methods and store the level locally.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Template->output() now accepts a variable length argument list of
			FieldSets or hash tables.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Actions are now passed a reference to the Harmoni object.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Databases now have a toDBDate() and fromDBDate() function to convert
			to the necessary Date format.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Completed ActionHandler, LoginHandler and Harmoni classes and
			services.
		</new>
		<change author='dobo'>
			Deprecated the createDatabase() method in DBHandler. Use
			addDatabase(), instead.	This change was provoked by the fact that

			Oracle requires different arguments to instantiate the DB object.
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added RGBcolor and HTMLcolor classes.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Finished Layout, Theme and Template.
		</change>
		<change>
			AuthenticationMethod includes changed to avoid random unprintable
			character output.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			FieldSetValidator and RuleSet now take optional argument on 
			validate()/validateAll() functions specifying if errors should be
			thrown upon failure or not.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			RuleSet can now accept an ErrorHandler to use via setErrorHandler().
		</change>
		<new author='dobo'>
			DBHandler can now use a PostgreSQL server and fetching last insert
			ID works on all integrated DBs.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			layoutHandler now works. Theme integration is to come.
		</change>
		<new author='max'>
			Database file storage method.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added interfaces for: VisualComponent, Layout, Menu, Content -- all
			part of the LayoutHandler.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			AuthenticationResult now holds authenticated agent's system name as
			well as valid methods.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			AgentInformationHandler now handles compiling of search results and
			returns the appropriate array format.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			AuthenticationMethod::getAgentInformation now returns an associative
			array of [username]=>array([key1]=>value1,...),...
		</change>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Change-Log now held in an XML file and translated by XSL!
		</new>
	</version>
	<version number="0.0.1" date="2003-07-10">
		<change author='gabe'>
			Changed AuthenticationMethod to allow for
			getAgentInformation(username,searchMode) so that one can search for 
			a username/fullname etc as well as get information for a single
			entry.
		</change>
		<new author='max'>
			Added StatisticsHandler.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Updated DB and LDAP AuthenticationMethods to allow for user-info
			searching &amp; tested backwards compatibility.
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			Changed naming scheme of packages so that they describe more clearly
			what they DO as opposed to what they CONTAIN.
		</change>
	</version>
	
	<about>
		The Harmoni Project is an effort led by the Curricular Technologies group at Middlebury College to build an application framework and standards-based infrastructure bus to support the rapid development and easy maintenance of curricular it projects. The project is built entirely using PHP's OOP (Object Oriented Programming) model, allowing the framework code to be easily extended and enhanced.
		
		At the core of the Harmoni Application Framework is an implementation of The Open Knowledge Initiative's (O.K.I) Open Service Interface Definitions (OSIDs). The OSIDs are a standard service-oriented API that defines a broad set of services that are germane to IT projects in the education field yet also fitting for broader uses.
		
		Sitting alongside of the Harmoni services is the "Harmoni Architecture". The "architecture" is a set of controllers and templates that coordinate configuration of services, the proper execution of application actions, and any post-processing of application output. The architecture is built on a popular module/action model, in which your PHP program contains multiple modules, each of which contain multiple executable actions. All you, as an application developer, need to write are the action files, not the controller logic.

		The "Harmoni Architecture" is separate from the Harmoni Services and either can be used independently of the other. 
	</about>
	
	<info>
		<title>Downloads</title>
		<description>For the latest and archived versions, please download from SourceForge:</description>
		<url>http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=82873</url>
	</info>
	<info>
		<title>Documentation</title>
		<description>
			See the Harmoni wiki for online documentation:
		</description>
		<url>http://harmoni.sf.net/</url>
	</info>
	<info>
		<title>Bug Tracker</title>
		<url>https://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=82873&amp;atid=567473</url>
	</info>
	
	<authors>
		<name short="adam">Adam Franco</name>
		<name short="gabe">Gabe Schine</name>
		<name short="dobo">Dobo Radichkov</name>
		<name short="nik">Nikitas Stamatopoulos</name>
		<name short="niraj">Niraj Dhungel</name>
		<name short="chris">Christopher Shubert</name>
		<name short="alex">Alex Chapin</name>
		<name short="max">Max Ovsjanikovs</name>
		<name short="eric">Eric Janssen</name>
		<name short="zach">Zach Toups</name>
		<name short="karlie">Karlie Verkest</name>
		<name short="tim">Tim Bahls</name>
		<name short="john">John Lee</name>
	</authors>
	<reporters>
		<reporter short="alex">
			<name>Alex Chapin</name>
			<institution>Middlebury College</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="alex_chapin">
			<name>Alex Chapin</name>
			<institution>Middlebury College</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="adam">
			<name>Adam Franco</name>
			<institution>Middlebury College</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="adam_franco">
			<name>Adam Franco</name>
			<institution>Middlebury College</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="gabe">
			<name>Gabe Schine</name>
			<!-- <institution></institution> -->
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="chris_newton">
			<name>Chris Newton</name>
			<!-- <institution></institution> -->
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="jose_accino">
			<name>Jos Alfonso Accino</name>
			<institution>University of Mlaga</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="bryan_carson">
			<name>Bryan Carson</name>
			<institution>Middlebury College</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="hector_vila">
			<name>Hector Vila</name>
			<institution>Middlebury College</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="jeff_merriman">
			<name>Jeff Merriman</name>
			<institution>MIT</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="peter_wilkins">
			<name>Peter Wilkins</name>
			<institution>MIT</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="tom_coppeto">
			<name>Tom Coppeto</name>
			<institution>OnTapSolutions/O.K.I.</institution>
		</reporter>
		<reporter short="josh_abraham">
			<name>Josh Abraham</name>
			<institution>Rapid7, LLC.</institution>
		</reporter>
	</reporters>
	<reftypes>
		<reftype name="bug" group="82873" tracker='567473'/>
		<reftype name="fr" group="82873" tracker='567476'/>
		<reftype name="patch" group="82873" tracker='567475'/>
		
		<reftype name="concerto_bug" group="88266" tracker='586054'/>
		<reftype name="concerto_fr" group="88266" tracker='586057'/>
		<reftype name="concerto_patch" group="88266" tracker='586056'/>
		
		<reftype name="segue_bug" group="82171" tracker='565234'/>
		<reftype name="segue_fr" group="82171" tracker='565237'/>
		<reftype name="segue_patch" group="82171" tracker='565236'/>
		<reftype name="segue_security" group="82171" tracker='1098812'/>
	</reftypes>
</changelog>
