<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- this contains a subchapter of the Harmoni manual -->

<subchapter>
	<name>Database Handler</name>
	<section>
		<name>Introduction</name>
		<heading>Background</heading>
		<p>The Database Handler is probably the most complex classes/Services offered by Harmoni. The Harmoni DB Handler offers a way to interface with databases of different kinds using <b>identical</b> PHP code. This is something that is not found any <b>any other</b> database wrapper out there.
		Many other wrappers claim to be database-independent, but the reality is that every database has its little quirks. While most claim to conform to ANSI SQL, this is only the truth on a very basic level. Any database will support the statement:</p>
		
		<block>INSERT INTO table (id,name,email) VALUES (3,"John","john@company.com")</block>
		
		<p>While this is all fine and good for the simplest of applications, our work demands much more complex queries involving multiple JOIN clauses of various types, etcetera, etcetera. Unfortunately there is great variation among different database back-ends when it comes to complex queries.</p>
		
		<p>The Harmoni DB Handler solves this problem with but one minor setback: You can't use data-base specific functions (ie, a function only offered by one DB type). But, you can promise your clients a high level of interoperability and ease of integration. Why limit your target audience to only those that use MySQL when you could target MySQL, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server and others?</p>
		
		<heading>How we do it</heading>
		<p>The DB Handler employs the use of "query objects" instead of having the programmer actually write SQL statements like every other wrapper we've come accross.</p>
		
		<p>For any query to the database, you instantiate an object and set up your query through class functions. All the query information is stored in a universal format in the query object until told to send to a specific database, at which point database-specific SQL is generated. This allows you to write your program even before you have decided what back-end to use. Cool.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<name>Setting up a Connection</name>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<name>Select Queries</name>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<name>Insert Queries</name>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<name>Update Queries</name>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<name>Delete Queries</name>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<name>Generic Queries</name>
	</section>
</subchapter>
